<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>whiletruelearn</title><link>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on whiletruelearn</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 11:21:53 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://whiletruelearn.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Purpose</title><link>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/essays/purpose/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 11:21:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/essays/purpose/</guid><description>&lt;p>Okay. So this is going to be a difficult topic to write about. Difficult, because I need to do some soul searching to write about purpose, this thing that propels me to wake up,
do something and navigate this journey called &lt;strong>life&lt;/strong> . To put simply, what is the purpose that I seek in my life other than the act of mere survival? And i want to do all this in a way where i am not just doing virtue signalling or projecting an altruistic version of myself, but instead it becomes an attempt at trying to make an accurate and honest assessment of my thoughts on this topic so that it becomes a marker of this time that i can later revisit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>That thing about DSP</title><link>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/stories/dsp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/stories/dsp/</guid><description>&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if you had felt this before , but imagine you are doing some activity, something along the lines of walking on a crowded street with music over your ears and the street is quite busy with shopkeepers and people who are bargaining for groceries. Amidst such chaos , you seem to be lost somewhere, somewhere that is clearly not the present. The reason being you remember something, something that is funny and you let out a chuckle , your otherwise serious boring face acquires a smile , an honest one which doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about whether it is photogenic or not. The people who are walking opposite to you see the sudden transition in the face and thinks you are a weirdo, the biker who had just honked in front of you let out an unapologetic curse word. You walk away from the trouble and move away to the reality of present with much more optimism and a secret chant to yourself &amp;ldquo;Life is Good&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Forget someone?</title><link>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/stories/howto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/stories/howto/</guid><description>&lt;p>Forgetting someone is a difficult thing. Even when you think that you had sort of got over someone, there are these push buttons waiting to be activated in our brain which sends in waves of memories related to that person (whom we shall call as ‘Y’ going forward). The trigger occurs when we visit some particular place or do an activity that is usually associated with ‘Y’. Sometimes it gets triggered for no particular reason also . Anyhow , it is not a good feeling when the trigger hits and you are back again to square one thinking about ‘Y’ when you clearly know you should have totally forgot that person by now.
I thought about this for quite a bit of time today, maybe I owe the alcohol in my blood stream some credit for coming up with this thought all together. In this vague thought of mine, I imagine my silly little brain as something similar to an Operating System (OS) which i have fine grain control on. We have just identified a means to over ride the OS which mostly does shit that makes no sense and is full of erratic behaviors. Thanks to the most advanced brain programming technology, we now can send patches that will over ride the default behaviors and settings.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>To You Neha</title><link>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/stories/toyou/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/stories/toyou/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;What is your opinion on dowry ?&amp;rdquo; , she asked me while laying on the terrace with me looking at the starry night&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Stupid Question Neha. C&amp;rsquo;mon don&amp;rsquo;t spoil the night &amp;quot; , my eyes focussed on the luminous full moon at this time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She turned her head sideways so that she could see my face, My cold and dull response hasn&amp;rsquo;t gone so well with her.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Okay Rahul, another Question then. Hopefully you will like this one&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lifecycle; Story of Hypocrites</title><link>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/stories/lifecycle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/stories/lifecycle/</guid><description>&lt;p>So this is a story that I wrote while in college. I had this idea in my head of creating a short film of sorts and the story kind of became a bit like screenplay. Anyways this got published in the college magazine and my dear editor/ director friend Anuraj did promise me that he will convert this story to a short film one day. I am still waiting for that day :-D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/projects/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="projects">Projects&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>These are some of the open/inner source projects that I have worked on.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="termichesshttpsgithubcomwhiletruelearntermichess">&lt;a href="https://github.com/whiletruelearn/termichess">TermiChess&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Play chess on your terminal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="duluhttpsgithubcomwhiletruelearndulu">&lt;a href="https://github.com/whiletruelearn/dulu">Dulu&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>A small python library for doing OCR. Built on top of the florence2 vision model.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="pdf-chathttpsgithubcomwhiletruelearnpdf-chat">&lt;a href="https://github.com/whiletruelearn/pdf-chat">Pdf-chat&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Simple implementation of RAG for Q&amp;amp;A on pdf document.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="toy-dhthttpswwwyoutubecomwatchvbsoivl7_oxk">&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BsOIvL7_oXk">Toy DHT&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>A toy distributed hash table using consistent hashing, data replication, node addition and failover.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="whatthelanghttpsgithubcomindixwhatthelang">&lt;a href="https://github.com/indix/whatthelang">WhatTheLang&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>A python library for language detection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Collaborators : &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/manojlds/">Manoj&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>