<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>whiletruelearn</title><link>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on whiletruelearn</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 11:21:53 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://whiletruelearn.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Purpose</title><link>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/essays/purpose/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 11:21:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/essays/purpose/</guid><description>Okay. So this is going to be a difficult topic to write about. Difficult, because I need to do some soul searching to write about purpose, this thing that propels me to wake up, do something and navigate this journey called life . To put simply, what is the purpose that I seek in my life other than the act of mere survival? And i want to do all this in a way where i am not just doing virtue signalling or projecting an altruistic version of myself, but instead it becomes an attempt at trying to make an accurate and honest assessment of my thoughts on this topic so that it becomes a marker of this time that i can later revisit.</description></item><item><title>That thing about DSP</title><link>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/stories/dsp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/stories/dsp/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if you had felt this before , but imagine you are doing some activity, something along the lines of walking on a crowded street with music over your ears and the street is quite busy with shopkeepers and people who are bargaining for groceries. Amidst such chaos , you seem to be lost somewhere, somewhere that is clearly not the present. The reason being you remember something, something that is funny and you let out a chuckle , your otherwise serious boring face acquires a smile , an honest one which doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about whether it is photogenic or not.</description></item><item><title>How to Forget someone?</title><link>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/stories/howto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/stories/howto/</guid><description>Forgetting someone is a difficult thing. Even when you think that you had sort of got over someone, there are these push buttons waiting to be activated in our brain which sends in waves of memories related to that person (whom we shall call as ‘Y’ going forward). The trigger occurs when we visit some particular place or do an activity that is usually associated with ‘Y’. Sometimes it gets triggered for no particular reason also .</description></item><item><title>To You Neha</title><link>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/stories/toyou/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/stories/toyou/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;What is your opinion on dowry ?&amp;rdquo; , she asked me while laying on the terrace with me looking at the starry night
&amp;ldquo;Stupid Question Neha. C&amp;rsquo;mon don&amp;rsquo;t spoil the night &amp;quot; , my eyes focussed on the luminous full moon at this time.
She turned her head sideways so that she could see my face, My cold and dull response hasn&amp;rsquo;t gone so well with her.
&amp;ldquo;Okay Rahul, another Question then.</description></item><item><title>Lifecycle; Story of Hypocrites</title><link>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/stories/lifecycle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/stories/lifecycle/</guid><description>So this is a story that I wrote while in college. I had this idea in my head of creating a short film of sorts and the story kind of became a bit like screenplay. Anyways this got published in the college magazine and my dear editor/ director friend Anuraj did promise me that he will convert this story to a short film one day. I am still waiting for that day :-D</description></item><item><title/><link>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://whiletruelearn.github.io/projects/</guid><description>Projects These are some of the open source projects that I have worked on.
WhatTheLang A python library for language detection.
Vangogh A prisma like web-app that performs Fast Neural style transfer.
Collaborators : Bala , Anurag
Morpheus A toolkit for exploring fundamental algorithms in Linear Algebra.</description></item></channel></rss>